The island was empty,
Only ice and fire.
The Ash Tree shot up
With its crown to the skies.
That's how Isa was born.
And the Gibberlings with it.
Ase and Emla,
Weaved from branches.
Families multiplied,
Isa became crowded!
Boats go out to seas,
Foreign seas.
But the custom was followed,
And the young sprouts
Returned to the Tree
To keep watch.
Orcs from across the sea
Invaded our lands.
We defended the Tree
To our last breath!
An alliance was formed:
Heidruns, Zvergs,
Priden units.
.
The Orcs were expelled.
Peace was short-lived...
Our world was split,
And the seas were gone,
Families separated.
Void creatures
Came at night.
Forgetting fear and grief,
We fought to save our Ash!
Our neighbors became
Our new misfortune,
Beasts in white skins
Came down the mountains like an avalanche.
No matter how many times
We defeated the cruel Urun,
The enemy returned,
As though possessed.
Century after century, a secret
Was unraveled by the Spinners,
That the Urun are lead into battle
By an immortal leader.
The Spinners imprisoned
The spirit of the leader.
Soon peace reigned
Over the lands of Isa...
You, messengers of the Abyss,
Broke their spells!
Kharyskhan is free!
Trouble is coming!
Threads tell me
What I should see.
What the pattern tells us
Must be done.